January 24, 2008

The Planning Center Inc. Human Resources 1580 Metro Drive Costa Mesa, CA 92626

To whom it may concern:

Please accept the attached resumé for the Environmental Scientist/CEQA Planner opening advertised at The Planning Center website. I consider myself a "smart generalist" and have a sincere passion for environmental sciences and renewable energy research. I am currently an Astrophysics Ph.D. student at Michigan State University who is looking to follow his heart by pursuing a career in the development of, and investment in, sustainable end-user plans, systems, and products. I have not specifically studied in these areas, but my academic and research records demonstrate my proclivity for grasping, abstracting, and manipulating complex concepts and mental constructs. When given the opportunity, I've excelled at every intellectual and real-world endeavor thus far.

I am a valuable workplace asset for any development group because of my extensive experience with analyzing complex data, innovative technical skills, and ability to collaboratively, and independently, advance a group's research objectives. I feel The Planning Center is an ideal fit for someone like me: someone that is creative, motivated, and has that entrepreneurial spirit. The Planning Center's investment and planning goals will benefit from my addition. I have dedicated considerable time and effort over the last five years to making private investment in clean energy technology, materials development, and systems deployment. I am now eager to make an intellectual and tangible contribution to the field, and there is no better place to do this than as a part of the forward-thinking, cutting-edge efforts of The Planning Center.

Please contact me if there is any further information I can provide as you review my application. Thank you for your consideration.

Sincerely,

Kenneth W. Cavagnolo

KENNETH W. CAVAGNOLO

RESUMÉ

Office Address

Contact Information

Michigan State University Department of Physics & Astronomy 3265 Biomedical Physical Sciences Building East Lansing, MI 48824-2320

1111 Kimberly Dr. Apt. #7 Lansing, MI 48912 Phone: (517)-285-9062

E-mail: kencavagnolo@gmail.com

Web: www.pa.msu.edu/people/cavagnolo/

Education

Michigan State University

2005 - Present

Ph.D. Astrophysics, Expected August 2008

Thesis Title: "Virialization, Entropy, & Feedback in Clusters of Galaxies"

Advisors: Dr. Megan Donahue & Dr. G. Mark Voit

Michigan State University

2002 - 2005

M.S. Astrophysics, Magna Cum Laude

Dissertation Title: "Entropy Profiles of Cooling Flow Clusters"

Advisor: Dr. Megan Donahue

Georgia Institute of Technology

1998 - 2002

B.S. Physics, Magna Cum Laude

Senior Thesis: "Analysis of the Eclipsing Binary ET Tau"

Advisor: Dr. James Sowell

Research

Graduate Research Assistant

2003 - Present

Experience

Supervisor: Dr. Megan Donahue, Mich. St. Univ.

Studying clusters of galaxies via their X-ray properties to

investigate feedback mechanisms, galaxy evolution, and the process

of cluster virialization.

Graduate Research Assistant

2002 - 2003

Supervisor: Dr. Jack Baldwin, Mich. St. Univ.

Analyzing echelle spectra for use in studies of *s*-process abundances

in planetary nebulae.

Undergraduate Research Assistant

2000 - 2002

Supervisor: Dr. James Sowell, Georgia Tech

Obtaining orbital solution for the eclipsing Algol binary ET Tau via

UBV light curves and spectroscopic radial velocity curves.

Research Interests

- Renewable Energy
- Sustainable Growth
- Closed Loop Manufacturing
- Environmental Policy
- Global Climate Change

Fall 2006

Teaching Substitute Instructor Experience Course: "Visions of the Universe"

Gave lectures covering stellar evolution, supernovae, white dwarves, neutron stars, and black holes.

Physics Tutor Summer 2003

Course: "Introductory Honors Physics I & II"

Tutored physics students taking introductory physics courses such as classical mechanics, optics, and electromagnetism.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

2002 - 2003

Course: "Visions of the Universe"

Directed and supervised laboratories for non-calculus based astronomy course.

Honors

• College of Natural Science Dissertation Fellow	2007 - Present
American Astronomical Society Member	2002 - Present
American Physical Society Member	2002 - Present
Sigma Pi Sigma National Honor Society	2001 - Present
• Dean's List, Georgia Tech	1998-2002

Scientific Skills

- Profound skills in reducing and analyzing data taken with *Chandra* X-ray Telescope.
- Extensive experience with customizing and debugging CIAO and CALDB.
- Familiarity with multiwavelength analysis packages: AIPS, IRAF, and PYRAF.
- Fluent in PERL, IDL, LATEX and HTML.
- Working knowledge of C, FLASH, FORTRAN, MYSQL, SUPERMONGO, and TCL.
- Mastery of multiple computing architectures: DOS, Linux, Macintosh, and Windows.
- Expert of computer troubleshooting, maintenance, and system construction.

References

DR. MEGAN DONAHUE (517)-355-9200 ext. 2418 donahue@pa.msu.edu Michigan State University

DR. G. MARK VOIT (517)-355-9200 ext. 2419 voit@pa.msu.edu
Michigan State University

DR. JACK BALDWIN (517)-355-9200 ext. 2411 baldwin@pa.msu.edu Michigan State University

First Author Refereed **Papers**

"X-ray and Entropy Scaling Relations in Galaxy Clusters"

Cavagnolo, Kenneth W.; Voit, G. Mark; and Donahue, Megan

2008, in prep. for Astrophysical Journal

"Feedback Mechanisms in Galaxy Clusters and Alteration of ICM Entropy"

Cavagnolo, Kenneth W.; Donahue, Megan; and Voit, G. Mark

2008, in prep. for Astrophysical Journal

"Star Formation in BCGs: Resurrecting Conduction"

Cavagnolo, Kenneth W.; Donahue, Megan; and Voit, G. Mark

2008, near Astrophysical Journal Letters submission

"Athenaeum of Galaxy Cluster Entropy Profiles"

Cavagnolo, Kenneth W.; Donahue, Megan; Voit, G. Mark; and Sun, Ming

2007, Astrophysical Journal Supplement submitted

"X-ray Band Dependence of X-ray Temperatures in Galaxy Clusters"

Cavagnolo, Kenneth W.; Donahue, Megan; Voit, G. Mark; and Sun, Ming

2007, Astrophysical Journal submitted

Other Refereed **Papers**

"Star Formation, Radio Sources, Cooling X-Ray Gas and Galaxy Interactions in the Brightest Cluster Galaxy in 2A0335+096"

Donahue, Megan; Sun, Ming; O'Dea, Christopher P.; Voit, G. Mark; Cavagnolo, Ken-

neth W.

2007AJ....134...14D

"Entropy Profiles in the Cores of Cooling Flow Clusters of Galaxies"

Donahue, Megan; Horner, Donald J.; Cavagnolo, Kenneth W.; Voit, G. Mark 2006ApJ...643..730D

"s-Process Abundances in Planetary Nebulae"

Sharpee, Brian; Zhang, Yong; Williams, Robert; Pellegrini, Eric; Cavagnolo, Kenneth;

Baldwin, Jack A.; Phillips, Mark; Liu, Xiao-Wei

2007ApJ...659.1265S

Presented Work & Talks

INVITED TALK: "The Effect of Cluster Feedback on High-Precision Cosmology"

Feb. 2008 – NASA National Space Science and Technology Center, UAH-Huntsville

INVITED TALK: "Understanding Feedback in Galaxy Clusters"

Jan. 2008 Center for Study of Cosmic Evolution Seminar, Michigan State University

INVITED TALK: "Band Dependence of X-ray Temperatures"

Oct. 2007 University of Michigan Astrophysics Seminar

POSTER: "The Entropy-Feedback Connection and Quantifying Cluster Virialization"

Cavagnolo, Kenneth W.; Donahue, Megan; Voit, G. Mark; and Sun, Ming

2007 Eight Years of Science with Chandra Symposium

POSTER: "Chandra Studies of Dark Matter and Galaxy Formation: Signatures from

the Intracluster Medium"

Donahue, Megan; Sun, M.; Cavagnolo, K.; Voit, G. 2006 Winter Meeting of the American Astronomical Society

PROCEEDING: "Abundances of s-process elements in planetary nebulae: Br, Kr & Xe" Zhang, Y.; Williams, R.; Pellegrini, E.; Cavagnolo, K.; Baldwin, J. A.; Sharpee, B.; Phillips, M.; Liu, X.-W. 2006 IAU Symposium

POSTER: "Studies of Entropy Distributions in X-ray Luminous Clusters of Galaxies" Cavagnolo, K. W.; Donahue, M. E.; Voit, G. M.; Sun, M.; Evrard, A. E. 2005 Winter Meeting of the American Astronomical Society

POSTER: "Entropy Distributions in the Cores of Nearby X-ray Luminous Clusters of Galaxies"

Cavagnolo, K. W.; Donahue, M. E.; Voit, G. M.; Horner, D. J.; Evrard, A. E. 2004 Winter Meeting of the American Astronomical Society

POSTER: "Radio-Free Cluster Cooling Flows"
Donahue, M. E.; Voit, G. M.; Cavagnolo, K.
2004 Winter Meeting of the American Astronomical Society

Personal Interests

- Academic: environmental sciences, "Cradle2Cradle" design, and urban planning.
- Athletics: triathlons, baseball, and everything Georgia Tech.
- Hobbies: reading, building model airplanes, and raising bonsai trees.